JOHN CHARBONNEAU



OBJECTIVE

To advance into a career in financial reporting or financial administration with a leading organization that will utilize my extensive financial analytics knowledge while also allowing me to develop further as a professional

Self-motivated, efficient, and highly organized Financial Reporting Analyst with five years of experience in fast-paced environments. Growth-focused thought leader seeking to leverage past experience in financial analytics, reporting, regulatory compliance, auditing, and account reconciliations to advance into a new career opportunity in financial reporting. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as presentation, forecasting, and problem-solving expertise.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Accounting Principles
- General Ledger
- Operational/Performance Improvement
- Communication
- Presentation Skills
- · Critical Thinking
- Tax Skills

- Financial Reporting
- Operational Analytics/Reporting
- Business Intelligence
- Regulatory Compliance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BNP PARIBAS, DENVER, CO, NOVEMBER 2019 TO PRESENT

AVP FINANCIAL REPORTING ANALYST

- Chart successful course of assembling monthly and quarterly shareholder reports, including the footnotes.
- Align objectives and bridge communications with the necessary business units such as Accounting and Business Improvement to ensure shareholder reports are ready for auditor reviews by the established deadlines.
- Orchestrate monthly regulatory Form N-PORT Filings as well as update and upkeep affiliated investments utilized in Annual and Semi-Annual investor books.
- Evaluate, update, and improve financial reporting workflows and processes to automate/streamline reporting operations.
- Cultivate up-to-date knowledge on changes to accounting standards, financial regulations, and regulatory reporting requirements, and assess impact on the company's reporting operations.
- Assist in implementing new accounting and financial reporting requirements to maintain regulatory compliance.
- Provide data analytics support, interpretation, and data problem-solving services to relevant business units.
- Initiate and document research into complex accounting and reporting manners to inform day-to-day operations.

COMPUTERSHARE, HIGHLANDS RANCH, CO, MAY 2017 TO OCTOBER 2019

LEAD ESCROW ASSOCIATE

- Executed vendor audits and reconciliations to carry out quality assurance measures and enforce compliance with RESPA.
- Verified accounts were administered in accordance with applicable regulations, local laws, and internal policies.
- Supported team members in the completion of various administrative tasks, including collection and review of transaction documentation, daily report reviews, maintenance of internal spreadsheets and databases, and execution of project tasks.
- Analyzed existing escrow processes to identify deficiencies and formulate improvement while maintaining a strong
 focus on internal and regulatory controls. Examples of which include conducting User Acceptance Testing of
 numerous Fiserv software updates, as well as improving upon the efficiency datapoints we presented on our
 monthly team "scorecard."

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

THE GARLIC KNOT, DENVER, CO, AUGUST 2017 TO MAY 2018 | **HEAD DELIVERY DRIVER**STARBUCKS, DENVER, CO, MARCH 2017 TO OCTOBER 2017 | **BARISTA**IKEA, CENTENNIAL, CO, SEPTEMBER 2011 TO SEPTEMBER 2015 | **LOGISTICS/SWEDISH FOOD MARKET WORKER**

JOHN CHARBONNEAU Page 2

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN FINANCE, 2017

Metropolitan State University of Denver, Denver, CO Led a team in delivering a presentation of a Risk/Return in a Managerial Finance course

AWARDS AND HONORS

Nominated for the Help-A-Colleague Award for training new analysts (BNP Paribas, 2021) **Awarded** two special bonuses for demonstrating outstanding motivation and achieving exceptional results in reporting duties (Computershare, 2019)

VOLUNTEERISM

Johnson Adult Day Center – 2008, 2009 Food Bank of the Rockies – 2022

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Proficiencies: SQL Server 2008 R2, Microsoft Office Suite (Excel VBA and Modeling), ACES Audit Software, data consolidation

Interests: Football, Basketball, Theatre Acting, Hiking, Camping, White Water River Rafting, Music, Traveling